别悲伤 将军
Don't grieve, Admiral.
这是我必须做的事
It is logical.
牺牲小我...
The needs of the many outweigh...
或是自我牺牲...
...the needs of the few.
才能成全大我
Or the one.
我永远都是你最好的朋友
I have been and always shall be your friend.
愿你平安快乐
Live long and prosper.
我们今天齐聚在这里送我们的战友最后一程
We are assembled here today to pay final respects to our honoured dead.
他的死亡象徵着新的生命...
This death takes place in the shadow of new life,
带来了新的世界
the sunrise of a new world.
他牺牲了生命去保卫这个世界
A world that our beloved comrade gave his life to protect.
他不觉得他的牺牲是无谓的
He did not feel this sacrifice a vain or empty one.
在我所有的朋友中...
Of my friend, I can only say this:
在进取号所有的成员中...
Of all the souls I have encountered in my travels,
他才是最具...
his was the most...
人性的一位
...human.
敬礼 发射
Honours. Hup!
太空是最终的边境
Space, the final frontier.
星舰进取号将要继续执行任务
These are the continuing voyages of the Starship Enterprise.
去探索陌生的国度
Her ongoing mission to explore strange new worlds.
去寻找新的生命跟新的文明
To seek out new lifeforms and new civilisations.
勇往直前...
To boldly go...
航行到无人踏足过的领域
...where no man has gone before.
《星际迷航3：石破天惊》
进取号舰长航行日志
USS Enterprise, Captain's Personal Log.
重创修复后 我们立即返航
With most of our battle damage repaired, we're almost home.
但我却感到心神不宁 我也不知道原因
Yet I feel uneasy. And I wonder why.
或许是因为这艘星舰太空旷
Perhaps it is the emptiness of this vessel.
大部分人员都已经被重新分配
Most of our trainee crew has been reassigned.
莎维可军官与我的儿子大卫
Lieutenant Saavik and my son David
正在他创造出来的创世星上继续进行实验
are exploring the Genesis planet, which he helped create.
而进取号就像一间人去楼空的房子
And Enterprise feels like a house with all the children gone.
不 比那感觉更空虚
No, more empty even than that.
史波克之死 就像一道永不愈合的伤口
The death of Spock is like an open wound.
我似乎将我最崇高的部分...
It seems that I've left the noblest part of myself back there...
遗留在创世星上
...on that newborn planet.
苏鲁 报告情况 好的 将军
Status, Mr Sulu. On course, Admiral.
估计在2.1个小时后到达地球
Estimating space dock in 2.1 hours.
非常好 契可夫 我要在到达前进行一次扫瞄
Very well. Mr Chekov, I'll need a pre-approach scan.
请到科学站去 好的
Take the science station, please. Yes, sir.
乌胡拉...进行创世计划的星舰有任何回应吗?
Uhura... Any response from Starfleet on our Project Genesis enquiries?
舰长 没有任何反应 这非常奇怪
No, sir, there is no response. That's very odd.
史考特 进度报告 快完成了 舰长
Scotty, progress report. It's almost done, sir.
星舰在抵达地球时 将可以恢复正常操作
You'll be fully automated by the time we dock.
时间配合的非常好
Excellent timing. You fixed the barn door after the horse has come home.
之后还要修理多久我们才可以再次出航?
How much refit time till we can take her out again?
八星期 但是因为时间紧迫 我会在两星期内完成
Eight weeks, sir. But you don't have eight weeks, so I'll do it in two.
你总会把你的估计时间乘以四倍吗?
Have you always multiplied your repair estimates by a factor of four?
当然 不然我如何能保持工作神速的美号?
Certainly, sir. How else can I keep my reputation as a miracle worker?
史考特 这个美号你当之无愧
Your reputation is secure, Scotty.
苏鲁 你来接管指挥我会在我的舱房内
Mr Sulu, take the Con. I'll be in my quarters.
舰长?
Sir?
我们到达时 他们会举行仪式吗?
Are they planning a ceremony when we get in?
我意思是迎接仪式 你想要英雄式的欢迎?
I mean, a reception? Would you like a hero's welcome?
也许吧
Well, God knows there should be.
这次我们付出了很大的代价
This time we've paid for the party with our dearest blood.
镇定一点...
Steady. Steady, boys.
继续扫瞄
Keep scanning.
我以为可以信赖你们 他到底在哪里?
I thought you people were reliable. Where the hell is he?
他已经待在这里很久了 启动呼叫频率
He's been here for some time. Put me on hailing frequency.
柯鲁奇司令...这是瓦克莉丝
Commander Kruge... This is Valkris.
我已经获得创世计划的资料 可以随时传送
I have purchased the Genesis data. Ready to transmit.
做得好 瓦克莉丝
Well done, Valkris.
到底是怎么一回事...
What the hell is...
解除隐形罩
Disengage cloaking device!
传送资料 开始
Transmit data. Now!
传送完成
Transmission completed.
你会发现它很有用处
You will find it useful.
意思是你已经看过了?
Then you have seen it?
是的 司令
I have, my Lord.
太不幸了
Unfortunate.
我明白了
Understood.
启动火箭推进器
Thrusters.
到底发生了什么事? 我何时可以拿到钱?
What the hell's going on? When do I get paid off?
很快就可以了 舰长
Soon, Captain. Quite soon.
祝你成功 司令...我爱你
Success, my Lord... and my love.
你将会名垂千古
You will be remembered with honour.
开火
Fire!
新方向 联邦中立地带
New course. Federation neutral zone.
喂它
Feed him!
是的 司令
Yes, my Lord.
控制中心 这里是进取号 已经准备返航
Approach Control, this is Enterprise, ready for docking manoeuvre.
进取号可以返航了 锁定系统
Enterprise is cleared to dock. Lock on.
系统已经锁定
Systems locked.
太空中心 让你们来控制了 没问题 进取号
Spacedock, you have control. Affirmative, Enterprise.
享受旅程 欢迎返航 进取号确认
Enjoy the ride, and welcome home. Enterprise confirms.
报告 己关闭大门
Acknowledge, doors closed.
你们看看那边
Would you look at that!
那是个很伟大的发明
My friends, the great experiment.
它就是精益号 已经随时可以试航了
The Excelsior. Ready for trial runs.
它应该配备了超级曲速引擎
She's supposed to have transwarp drive.
它真是太先进了
And if my grandmother had wheels, she'd be a wagon.
时代进步了 史考特 接受新事物吧
Young minds, fresh ideas. Be tolerant, Mr Scott.
悬挂及重力系统...准备
Standby umbilical and gravitational support systems.
知道 长官 开始停泊 所有系统进入准备状态
Aye, sir, moorings activated, all systems standing by.
将军 这太不可能了 契可夫
Admiral. This is not possible. Mr Chekov.
史波克的房间有能量的迹象
An energy reading from 'C' deck, from inside Mr Spock's quarters.
我已经下令封锁他的房间 是我亲自封锁的
I ordered Spock's quarters sealed. I sealed the room myself!
但是里面显示有生命的迹象
Nevertheless, I am reading a lifeform there.
我们为了史波克都快发疯了
This entire crew seems on the edge of obsessive behaviour regarding Spock.
安全系统报告 有人闯入史波克的房间
Sir, Security reports the door to Spock's quarters has been forced.
我马上赶去 苏鲁 继续停泊程序
I'm on my way. Sulu, continue docking procedures.
詹姆士...
Jim...
救救我
Help me.
你把我留在创世星 你为何要这么做?
You left me on Genesis. Why did you do that?
救救我
Help me.
麦考伊...
Bones!
你到底在做什么?
What the hell are you doing?
你疯了吗?
Have you lost your mind?
救救我 詹姆士 带我回家
Help me, Jim. Take me home.
麦考伊 我们已经到家了
Bones, we are. We are home.
那么或许还不太晚
Then perhaps it's not too late.
爬上阶梯
Climb the steps, Jim.
爬上史莱亚山
Climb the steps of Mount Seleya.
史莱亚山?
Mount Seleya?
麦考伊 史莱亚山在瓦肯星 我们己回到地球了
Bones, Mount Seleya's on Vulcan. We're home... on Earth.
记得
Remember.
将军 己完成降落
Admiral, docking is completed.
星际舰队的马洛将军 已经在等候检阅
Starfleet Commander Morrow is on his way for inspection.
乌胡拉 快叫医护人员来这儿 叫他们马上来
Uhura, get the medics down here! Get them now!
你们在最艰难的情况下 完成了非凡的任务
You've all done remarkable service under the most difficult conditions.
你们将会收到星际舰队最高的赞赏
You'll be receiving Starfleet's highest commendation.
更重要的是特别延长的假期
And more importantly... extended shore leave.
除了史考特先生以外 因为精益号需要你的帮忙
All but you, Mr Scott. They need your wisdom on the new Excelsior.
明天去那里报到 是工程舰长的职位
Report there tomorrow as Captain of Engineering.
我很感激 但我宁愿留下来修理进取号
With all appreciation, I'd prefer to supervise the refit of Enterprise.
恐怕那己不需要了
I'm afraid that won't be necessary.
但是 长官...
But, sir...
我很抱歉 史考特先生 进取号将不会被修理
I'm sorry, Mr Scott, but there will be no refit.
将军 我不明白 进取号并不...
Admiral... I don't understand. The Enterprise is not...
进取号已有20年的舰龄 我们觉得它应该退役了
Jim, the Enterprise is 20 years old. We feel her day is over.
但我们已经要求...
But we had requested...
我们希望带它回去创世星
We had hoped to take her back to Genesis.
那是不可能的 我可以知道原因吗?
That is out of the question. May I ask why?
你可能不知道 创世星惹起了很大的争议
In your absence, Genesis has become a galactic controversy.
在星球联邦议会定下政策之前
Until the Federation Council makes policy,
你们绝对不能跟任何人...
you are all under orders not to discuss with anyone
谈论关於创世星的事
your knowledge of Genesis.
就将它当成是被隔离的星球 被禁止谈论的话题
Consider it a quarantine planet... and a forbidden subject.
为了明白这个事件
To understand the events on which I report, it is necessary to review
你们必须了解创世机的理论
the theoretical data on the Genesis device,
创世机是由两位马库斯博士所研究的
as developed by Doctors Carol and David Marcus.
他们希望从无生命的环境中创造出生命来
Genesis, simply put, is life from lifelessness.
我们把创世机放到一颗没有生命的星球
The device was to be introduced into a pre-selected area
例如一颗月球或其他的星球
of a lifeless space body, a moon or other dead form.
那个装置会马上产生创世效应
The device would instantaneously cause the Genesis efect.
将一个无生命的月球变成一个生气盎然的行星
Instead of a dead moon, a living, breathing planet now exists,
能够维持任何生命体的生活
capable of sustaining whatever life forms we see fit to deposit on it.
如何?
So?
你说
Speak.
这是很值得控制的强大力量
Great power to control, dominate.
你说 非常厉害
Speak. Impressive.
他们可以创造出一个行星来
They can make a planet.
没错 新的城市、新的家园...
Oh, yes. New cities, homes in the country.
妻子跟孩子都陪伴在你身边
Your woman at your side, children playing at your feet.
而且星球联邦的旗子 会在头上随风飘扬
And overhead, fluttering in the breeze, the flag of the Federation!
迷人吗?
Charming.
回到岗位上 是的 司令
Station. Yes, my Lord.
别跟任何人提起这件事 明白 司令
Share this with no one. Understood, my Lord.
我们要前往那颗行星
We are going to this planet.
尽管我们的使者 正在跟星球联邦议和
Even as our emissaries negotiate for peace with the Federation,
但是为了保护我们的人民 我们必须采取行动
we will act for the preservation of our race.
我们将要夺取这个秘密武器
We will seize the secret of this weapon.
这个超级秘密武器
The secret of ultimate power!
祝你成功 司令
Success, my Lord.
我们已经抵达035方位的行星
We have reached the destination planet at point 035.
非常好 中尉
Very well, Lieutenant. Helm.
控制室 以标准轨道前进
Execute standard orbital approach.
传送密码口信给星际舰队司令 第一优先
Send a coded message for Starfleet Commander, Priority One.
星联科学太空舰葛里松号刚刚抵达创世星
"Federation science vessel Grissom arriving Genesis, Mutara Sector,"
即将开始进行实验 指挥官艾斯塔班
"to begin research. J.T. Esteban commanding."
马库斯博士 这是你的行星
Dr Marcus, it's your planet.
请开始扫瞄
Begin scanning, please.
莎维可 好玩的地方现在才开始
This is where the fun begins, Saavik.
跟你父亲一样 太像人类了
Just like your father, so human.
所有单位启动 开动记录器 扫瞄领域一
All units functional. Recorders are on. Scanning Sector 1.
树叶生长茂盛 气温摄氏22.2度
The foliage in fully developed state of growth. Temperature 22.2 Celsius.
领域二是沙漠地带 极少量植物 气温39.4
Sector 2 indicating desert terrain. Minimal vegetation. Temperature 39.4.
领域三是亚热带植物
Sector 3, sub-tropical vegetation.
气温急速下降
Temperature decreasing rapidly.
下雪 这个领域会下雪 真是难以置信
It's snow. Snow in the same sector. Fantastic!
太迷人了
Fascinating.
这个小星球具备了地球上的各种地形与天气
All the varieties of land and weather known to Earth, within hours' walk.
有金属物体 执行短距离扫瞄
Metallic mass. Close range scan.
是一个光量子管
A photon tube.
重力场显示它是安全著陆的
Gravitational fields were in flux. It must have soft landed.
马上通知星际舰队
In code to Starfleet:
史波克舰长的棺木位於创世星的表面
"Captain Spock's tube located on Genesis surface."
真令人无法置信
I don't believe it.
怎么了?
What is it?
如果设备运行正常的话 讯号显示有动物生命迹象
If equipment is functioning properly, indications are an animal lifeform.
你说那里没有动物的 是不该有的
You said there wouldn't be any. There shouldn't be.
讯号已经被证实 显示有不明生命体
Cross referenced and verified. An unidentifiable lifeform reading.
长官 你要通知星际舰队吗?
You wish to advise Starfleet, sir?
我们根本不知道那是什么
We don't know what we're talking about here.
我们为何不将他传送上来? 不行
Why don't we beam it up? Oh, no.
条例清楚说明：除非不会有被污染的危险
Regulations state, "Nothing shall be beamed aboard"
否则任何东西都不能被传送上来
"until danger of contamination is eliminated."
舰长 我们可以派人下去检查
Captain, beaming down to the surface is permitted.
除非任务是必要而且安全的
If the Captain decides that the mission is vital and reasonably safe.
我们必须查明那是什么 或者是谁
Please, we must see what it is. Or who.
敬缺席的朋友
Absent friends.
将军 进取号将会如何?
Admiral, what's going to happen to the Enterprise?
它会退役 我们会有另一艘星舰吗?
She's to be decommissioned. Will we get another ship?
我不知道 星际舰队正忙于参加宇宙会议
I can't get an answer. Starfleet's up to its brass in galactic conference.
没人有空处理这种不要紧的事
No one has time for those who stand and wait.
麦考伊医生如何了?
Sir, about Dr McCoy, how is he?
他被注射了很多镇定剂 正在家里修养
He's home, resting comfortably, pumped full of tranquilizers.
他们说他是精疲力竭 他保证会在家好好修养
They say it's exhaustion. He promised he'd stay put. We'll see.
应该是史考特
Ah, Mr Scott.
进来
Come.
沙瑞克!
Sarek!
大使 我不知道你会来 你应该见过我的舰队人员
Ambassador, I had no idea you were here. I believe you know my crew.
我想单独跟你谈谈 寇克
I will speak with you alone, Kirk.
请大家回避一下
Please excuse us.
大使 我应该前去瓦肯星 向你慰问一下
Ambassador, I would have come to Vulcan to express my deep sympathy.
省省这些陈腔滥调 我已经去过你们的星联政府
Spare me your human platitudes, Kirk. I have been to your Government.
我看过创世星的资料 还有你的报告
I have seen the Genesis information, and your own report.
那你应该知道 你儿子是非常勇敢
Then you know how bravely your son met his death.
你为何将他留在创世星?
Why did you leave him on Genesis?
史波克很信任你 但是你却离弃了他
Spock trusted you. And you denied him his future.
我没有离弃他 他只是身体死亡而已
I saw no future. Only his body was in death, Kirk.
你是最后跟他在一起的人
And you were the last one to be with him.
你必定知道 你应该将他带回瓦肯星去
Then you must know that you should have come with him to Vulcan.
为什么? 因为他要求你这么做
But why? Because he asked you to!
他将他肉体以外的东西...
He entrusted you...
全都交托给你
...with his very essence, with everything that was not of the body!
他要求你把他带回来
He asked you to bring him to us.
把他的灵魂带回来
And to bring that which he gave you: His Katra. His living spirit.
先生...
Sir...
我非常疼爱你的儿子
Your son meant more to me than you can know.
我愿意用我的生命去交换他的生命
I'd have given my life if it would have saved his.
但是诘你相信我 他没有要求我带他回来
Believe me when I tell you... he made no request of me.
他只是没有公开说出来而己
He would not have spoken of it openly.
那么我怎会知道...
Then how was...
我要进入你的思想 可以吗?
I must have your thoughts. May I join your mind?
当然可以
Certainly.
他谈到跟你的友谊
He spoke of your friendship.
是
Yes.
他...叫你别悲伤
He... asked you not to grieve.
是
Yes.
牺牲小我...
The needs of the many...
或是...
...outweigh...
自我牺牲...
...the needs of the few...
才能成全大我
...or the one.
史波克
Spock...
我永远都是...
I have been...
你的朋友
...and always shall be your friend.
愿你平安快乐
Live long and prosper.
不
No.
请原谅我
Forgive me.
他不在这里
It is not here.
我还以为他的灵魂 已经跟你结合在一起
I had assumed he mind-melded with you.
那是瓦肯星人的求存方法
It is the Vulcan way... when the body's end is near.
我们被分开了
We were separated.
他没办法摸到我
He couldn't touch me.
我明白了
I see.
那么他的一切...
Then everything that he was...
他拥有的知识...
...everything he knew...
全都消失了
...is lost.
请等一等
Please wait.
如果事情那么重要 他一定会找别的办法
He would have found a way. If there was that much at stake,
史波克一定会找别的办法
Spock would have found a way.
对 但是他会如何做呢?
Yes. But how?
也许他会将灵魂附在其他人身上
What if he joined with someone else?
引擎室 飞行录影记录 星历8128.78
Engine Room, Flight Recorder Visual. Star date 8128. 78.
播放
Go.
星舰安全吗?
Ship... out of danger?
是
Yes.
回带 0.77
Back, 0.77.
飞行影像记录 28.77
Flight Recorder Visual, 28. 77.
停止 你这样会让引擎室淹没
No! You'll flood the whole compartment!
他会没命的 舰长 他已经死了
He'll die. Captain! He's dead already.
回带 0.76
Back, 0.76.
飞行影像记录 28.76
Flight Recorder Visual, 28. 76.
你不要进去 也许你是对的
You're not going in there! Perhaps you're right.
史考特的情况如何? 我猜他大概...
What is Mr Scott's condition? I don't think that he...
很抱歉 我没时间跟你详细解释
Sorry, Doctor, I have no time to discuss this logically.
停止
Freeze.
重复播放...放大画面
Repeat... and augment.
记著...
Remember...
是麦考伊!
McCoy!
个生存 一个死亡 但是双方都很痛苦
One alive, one not. Yet both in pain.
我现在该如何做?
What must I do?
你必须带他们到瓦肯星的史莱亚山
You must bring them to Mount Seleya on Vulcan.
只有在那里 他们才会找到平安
Only there can both find peace.
这个要求...
What you ask...
真的非常困难
...is difficult.
寇克 你会有办法的
You will find a way, Kirk.
你一定要帮助他们
If you honour them both, you must.
我会的
I will.
我发誓
I swear.
传送室 请准备传送
Transporter Room, stand by to energise.
知道 长官 正在准备传送
Aye, sir, energising now.
葛里松号通知莎维可 我们探测到生命体的辐射
Grissom to Saavik. We're picking up radiation from the lifeform.
知道 舰长 我们的读数仍然很安全
Affirmative, Captain. Our readings are well below danger level.
千万要小心 中尉
Exercise caution, Lieutenant.
这次行动是由我批准的 我需要对你们的安全负贵
This landing is Captain's discretion, and I'm the one who's out on a limb.
我会记著这点
I'll try to remember that.
你们探测到的只是棺木表面的细菌而己
There are your lifeforms. These were microbes on the tube's surface.
我们从进取号射它们下来的 它们繁殖的很快
We shot them here from Enterprise. They were fruitful and multiplied.
为什么它们进化的那么快呢?
But how could they have evolved so quickly?
莎维可...
Saavik...
这是什么东西?
What is it?
是史波克的尸衣
Spock's burial robe.
绝对不可以 詹姆斯 你是我最好的军官
No, absolutely not, Jim. You're my best officer.
但我是星舰的司令官 我不可以违反条例
But I am Commander, Starfleet, so I don't break rules.
别跟我说什么条例 我说的是忠实跟牺牲
Don't quote rules to me. I'm talking about loyalty and sacrifice.
我们牺牲了一个队员 另一个也有严重的精神问题
One man who's died for us, another with deep emotional problems.
这次关于史波克跟麦考伊的事
This business about Spock and McCoy...
老实说 我也不了解瓦肯星的魔法
Honestly, I never understood Vulcan mysticism.
你不用相信他们 我也不知道我是否相信
You don't have to believe. I'm not even sure that I believe.
但是如果史波克的灵魂 真的留下来了
But if there's even a chance that Spock has an eternal soul...
我就有责任帮助他 你的责任?
...then it's my responsibility. Yours?
绝对是我的责任
As surely as if it were my very own.
请你把进取号还给我 只要有史考特的帮忙...
Give me back the Enterprise. With Scotty's help I could...
你知道进取号是不能再飞的
The Enterprise would never stand the pounding, and you know it!
那么我就租一艘太空舰 不可能
Then I'll hire a ship. Out of the question, my friend.
联邦议会已经下令 只有科学部队可以到创世星
The Council has ordered that no one but the science team goes to Genesis.
你的生命跟事业代表著理智 不是冲动
Your life and your career stand for rationality, not intellectual chaos.
如果你继续这样 你将会失去一切
Keep up this emotional behaviour and you'll lose everything.
你将会前途尽毁 你明白吗?
You'll destroy yourself. Do you understand me, Jim?
我听见了
I hear you.
我试着帮忙而己
I had to try.
当然
Of course.
谢谢你 不客气
Thanks for the drink. Any time.
怎么了? 不行
The word, sir? The word...
不过我还是会去
...is no. I am therefore going anyway.
我们会帮助你的 要通知麦考伊医生吗?
You can count on our help, sir. Shall I alert Dr McCoy?
对 他将要飞很远的路程
Please. He has a long journey ahead of him.
很久不见 医生
Long time, Doc.
没错 有人找我吗?
Yeah. Anybody been looking for me?
我在找你呢 你要喝什么?
I have, but what's the use? What'll it be?
牛郎星的水 你很少喝这种毒药的
Altair water. That's not your usual poison.
来酒馆喝毒药 好像不是太合理吧
To expect one to order poison in a bar is not logical.
明白了
Got it.
敬你的行星 欢迎你
To your planet, welcome.
这应该是我说的 外星人 请原谅我
I think that's my line, stranger. Oh, forgive.
我只是新丁 你却是鼎鼎大名进取号的麦考伊医生
I here am new. But you are known, being McCoy from Enterprise.
我的处境好像很不利 我的名字并不重要
You have me at a disadvantage, sir. I name not important.
是你找我的 我收到你的讯息
You seek I. Message received.
我已经为你准备好太空舰
Available ship stands by.
需要多少钱? 何时可以起程?
How much and how soon?
现在就可以起程 价钱要看你想去哪儿
How soon is now. How much is where.
米塔拉领域 那儿是禁区
Somewhere in the Mutara Sector. Oh, Mutara restricted!
需要许可证跟很多的钱
Take permits many. Money more.
当然不会有许可证
There aren't going to be any damn permits!
违法的事怎么会有许可证?
How can you get a permit to do a damn illegal thing?
写下你的价钱 我付钱给你
Look... Price you name, money I got!
写下目的地 我才决定价钱 不然就没有交易了
Place you name, money I name, otherwise bargain, no.
好 我要去创世星...是创世星
All right, dammit! Genesis. The name of the place we're going is Genesis!
创世星?
Genesis?!
没错 是创世星 你的大耳朵有问题吗?
Yes, Genesis! How can you be deaf with ears like that?
创世星是禁区!
Genesis allowed is not! It's planet forbidden!
创世星的确是禁区 但是...
Look, my backward friend. Genesis may be planet forbidden, but I'm...
很抱歉 先生 你不该公开讨论这个
Sir, I'm sorry. You don't want to be discussing this subject in public.
我喜欢谈什么就谈什么 你到底是谁?
I'll discuss what I like! And who in the hell are you?!
你要我送你回家吗? 麦考伊医生?
Would you like a ride home, Dr McCoy?
傻子 如果我要回家 我还会租太空舰吗?
If I wanted a ride home, would I be trying to charter a space flight?
你为什么会知道我的名字?
How in the hell do you know who I am?
我是联邦警察
Federation Security, sir.
你得好好休息一下 医生
You're gonna get a nice long rest, Doctor.
莎维可通知葛里松号 我们探测到另一种生命体
Saavik to Grissom. We are definitely reading a second lifeform.
我们也探测到 请你小心行事
We concur. Proceed with caution, Saavik.
下面到底发生了什么事?
What the hell is going on down there?
将军 我们得快点 他们要将他移去联邦精神病院
Be quick, Admiral. They're moving him to the Federation 'Funny Farm'.
我可怜的朋友 我听说他很不稳定
Yes, poor friend. I hear he's fruity as a nutcake.
两分钟
Two minutes.
詹姆士
Jim!
我比出多少根手指头? 那一点都不有趣
How many fingers do I have up? That's not very damn funny.
你的幽默感恢复了 当然 那是什么?
Your sense of humour has returned. The hell it has. What's that?
清醒药 用来作什么?
Lexorin. Lexorin? What for?
你被瓦肯星人的灵魂附上了
You're suffering from a Vulcan mind-meld, Doctor.
那个绿血的王八蛋
That green-blooded son-of-a-bitch.
一定是他辩论输给我 就对我报复
It's his revenge for all those arguments he lost.
让我看看你的手 这会让你旅行时的状态好点
Let me see your hand. This will make you well enough to travel.
寇克将军在哪儿? 在里面
Where's Admiral Kirk? With the prisoner.
快叫他出来 星联司令要他马上过去
Get him quickly. Commander, Starfleet, wants him right away.
忙碌的一天?
Keeping you busy?
别自以为聪明 小个子
Don't get smart, Tiny.
将军 星联... 你快来看 他病得很严重
Admiral, Starfleet... This man's sick. Look.
搭右侧的电梯 执法人员已经赶来了
Side elevator. Agents on their way up.
别叫我小个子
Don't call me Tiny.
第二单位 这里是第一单位
Unit Two, this is unit One.
我们正要前往乐土
The Koyabashi Maru has set sail for the promised land.
消息收到 将会通知所有单位
Message acknowledged. All units will be informed.
你要带我去乐土?
You're taking me to the promised land?
谁叫我们是朋友呢?
What are friends for?
史考特先生...今晚到此为止?
Mr Scott... Calling it a night?
是的 老实说
Yes, sir. Turning in myself.
我很期望明天能打破进取号的速度纪录
Looking forward to breaking some of Enterprise's speed records tomorrow.
晚安
Good night.
请告知层数 输送室
Level, please. Transporter Room.
谢谢 要你们好看
Thank you. Up your shaft!
旧城控制室一切正常
Roger, Old City Station at 22.00 hours. All is well.
知道 所有控制室都维持正常
Understood. All stations clear.
司令 你让我感到很惊愕
You amaze me, Commander.
以一个20年经验的老手 你竟然选择最差的控制室
A 20-year space veteran, you choose the worst duty station in town.
你看看这个地方 这里非常偏僻
I mean, look at this place! This is the hind end of space.
我却认为这里很安宁平静
Peace and quiet appeals to me, Lieutenant.
或许快退休的人才会喜欢这里
Maybe that's okay for someone like you, whose career is winding down.
但我却需要一些挑战和冒险
But me, I need some challenge in my life, adventure.
或许只是一两个惊喜都不错
Maybe even just a surprise or two.
小心你许下的愿望
Well, you know what they say. Be careful what you wish for.
它们或许会成真
You may get it.
晚安 指挥官 一切都安好吧?
Good evening, Commander. Is everything ready?
各位 请进入我的接待室
Step into my parlour, gentlemen.
我的天 那是寇克将军 你说的没错
That's Admiral Kirk, my God. Very good for you, Lieutenant.
这很不合规则 没有目的地指示跟身分证明
But it's damn irregular. No destination orders, no encoded IDs.
一点也没错 我们应该怎么办?
All true. What are we going to do about it?
我什么都不做 但你却必须进去衣橱里
I'm not going to do anything, but you're going to sit in the closet.
你发疯了吗?
Have you lost all your sense of reality?
我没有发疯
This isn't reality.
这是幻想 你不是要冒险吗?
This is fantasy. You wanted adventure, how's this?
是否感到兴奋刺激呢? 好小子
The old adrenalin going, huh? Good boy.
现在进去衣橱里
Now get in the closet.
继续走 我会进去衣橱里的
Go on. Go on! I'll just get in the closet.
好的
Okay!
我很高兴你愿意帮忙 你应付得来吗?
I'm glad you're on our side. Can you handle that?
我会应付那个冒险小子的
I'll have Mr Adventure eating out of my hand, sir.
我们到时在老地方见 还有将军...
And I'll see all of you at the rendezvous. And Admiral...
我祝福你们
All my hopes.
就如我所保证的 它己准备就绪
As promised, she's all yours, sir. All systems automated and ready.
一只黑猩猩和两个新兵都可以驾驶它
A chimpanzee and two trainees could run her.
谢谢你 史考特 我会试着不去在意你说的话
Thank you, Mr Scott. I'll try not to take that personally.
朋友们 我不能再要求你们了
My friends, I can't ask you to go any further.
我和麦考伊医生必须这么做 但是你们不用
Dr McCoy and I have to do this. The rest of you do not.
将军 我们在浪费宝贵的时间
Admiral, we're losing precious time.
请告知航线 将军? 史考特?
What course, please, Admiral? Mr Scott?
将军 请你下达命令吧
I'd be grateful, Admiral, if you'd give the word.
各位 希望我们一路顺风 请各就各位
Gentlemen... May the wind be at our backs. Stations, please.
启动自动系统 是的 己启动
Engage auto systems. Aye. Engaged.
解除停泊程序 己解除
Clear all moorings. Cleared, sir.
四分一推动力 四分一推动力
One quarter impulse power. One quarter impulse.
星联司令紧急呼叫
Commander, Starfleet, on emergency channel.
他下令你立刻交出太空舰
He orders you to surrender this vessel.
契可夫 别答覆 苏鲁 平稳的开动
No reply, Chekov. Steady as she goes, Sulu.
黄色警戒 舰长立刻回复舰桥
Yellow Alert. Captain to the bridge.
我是舰长 太空停泊处怎么可能有黄色警戒?
This is the Captain. How can you have a Yellow Alert in spacedock?
有人正在偷取进取号
Sir, someone is stealing the Enterprise.
我马上赶来
I'm on my way.
黄色警戒 所有控制室 黄色警戒
Yellow Alert. All stations, Yellow Alert.
一分钟后到达太空门
One minute to spacedoors.
你要硬闽过大门吗? 冷静点
Are you gonna walk through them? Calm yourself.
精益号正启动引擎 准备追赶我们
Sir. Excelsior powering up with orders to pursue.
黄色警戒
Yellow Alert.
报告状态
Status.
自动系统已经准备就绪 取消自动停泊
All automates ready and functioning. Automatic moorings retracted.
超级曲速引擎已经准备妥当
All speeds available through Transwarp Drive.
很优秀的太空舰
Incredible machine.
控制室 四分之一推动力
Helm. One quarter impulse power.
三十秒后到达太空门
Thirty seconds to spacedoors.
警告 太空门紧闭
Warning, secured spacedoors.
就是现在 史考特 长官?
And now, Mr Scott. Sir?
打开大门 史考特 我知道 我正在想办法
The doors, Mr Scott! Aye, sir, I'm workin' on it.
危险 太空门紧闭 危险
Danger, spacedoors are closed. Danger.
我们己完全通过太空门
We have cleared spacedoors.
开启全速推动力 是的
Full impulse power. Aye, sir.
牵引杆准备 牵引杆己被开动
Standby tractor beam. Tractor beam, on.
如果他想用曲速引擎逃走 他准备大开眼界吧
If he tries to get away with Warp Drive, he's in for a shock.
精益号接近至四千公尺
Excelsior closing to 4,000 metres, sir.
史考特 是你表演的时候了 准备开动曲速引擎
We'll need everything you have. Warp Drive standing by.
寇克...
Kirk...
如果你这么做 你将失去舰长的位子
If you do this, you'll never sit in the Captain's chair again.
曲速引擎 是的 曲速引擎
Warp Speed. Aye, sir. Warp Speed.
准备开动曲速引擎
Prepare for Warp Speed. Stand by Transwarp Drive.
曲速引擎己准备妥当 开动全力
Transwarp at your command. Full power available.
执行
Execute.
开动...
...power available.
开动全力
Full power available.
曲速引擎全速前进 五、四、三、二、一
Transwarp Drive, maximum velocity in five, four, three, two, one.
史考特 做得漂亮
Scotty, as good as your word.
越先进的引擎 越容易被破坏
The more they overtake the plumbing, the easier to stop up the drain.
这个给你 医生 我给你的礼物
Here, Doctor, souvenirs from one surgeon to another.
我从他们的曲速引擎拿下来的
I took them out of her main Transwarp computer drive.
感谢你们预先告诉我 你没来参加开会
Nice of you to tell me in advance. You missed the staff meeting.
你们今天的表现非常杰出
Your work today has been outstanding.
不论未来你们被派到什么单位
I will recommend you all for promotion...
我都会尽力推荐你们 全力向创世星前进
...in whatever fleet we end up serving. Best speed to Genesis.
我是莎维可 你会说话吗?
I am Saavik. Can you speak?
创世波可能让他的细胞复活了
The Genesis Wave. His cells could have been regenerated.
舰长 我是莎维可 诘回答
Captain, this is Saavik. Come in, please.
是的 莎维可 请说 我们己找到生命体
Yes, Saavik, go ahead. We have found the life sign.
他是个瓦肯男孩 大约是地球上的八至十岁
It is a Vulcan child, perhaps eight to ten Earth years of age.
男孩? 他如何来到那里的? 马库斯博士认为...
A child?! How did he get there? It is Dr Marcus' opinion that...
创世波让史波克舰长复活了
...that the Genesis effect has in some way regenerated... Captain Spock.
莎维可 这真是...太异常了 你打算怎么做?
Saavik, that's... extraordinary. What would you like to do next?
请批准马上传送上太空舰
Request permission to beam aboard immediately.
马库斯博士认为 他有感染辐射的可能性吗?
Does Dr Marcus think there's any chance of radioactive contamination?
没有 他没侦察到任何辐射
No. None that he can detect, sir.
我得通知星际舰队 希望他们能给予指示
I'm going to advise Starfleet and get instructions.
我肯定星际舰队会批准的 但我们还是照规矩来吧
I'm sure Starfleet would approve. But let's do it by the book.
准备收发无线电报 开始传送
Standby on this channel. Go.
星际舰队控制室 葛里松号正在密码98.8频道
Starfleet Command, this is USS Grissom on coded channel 98.8.
请回话
Come in, please.
我们的电报被干扰 是一股很强的能量
Sir, something is jamming our transmission. An energy surge.
探查出位置
Locate!
从太空舰后方而来
Sir, it's from astern!
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
炮手...瞄准他们的引擎
Gunner... Target engine only.
舰长 发生了什么事? 我们受到攻击
Captain, what is happening? We're under attack!
准备躲避
Stand by for evasive.
发射
Fire.
我要俘虏他们的
I wanted prisoners!
射得太准确了...
A lucky shot, sir...
白痴
Animal!
司令 我可以建议... 说错话你就死定了
Sir, may I suggest... Say the wrong thing, Torg!
星球上有生命的迹象 或许是你想找的科学家
There are life signs on the planet. Perhaps the very scientists you seek.
莎维可呼叫葛里松号... 非常好
Saavik calling Grissom... Very good.
葛里松号 莎维可在紧急频道 请回答
Grissom, this is Saavik on emergency frequency. Come in, please.
他们发生了什么事?
What happened to them?
葛里松号似乎被敌人击落了
It would seem the Grissom was destroyed by an enemy attack.
我们必须走了 他们很快就会来追杀我们
We must go. They will soon come after us.
估计用现在的时速前进2.9钟头后就会到达创世星
Estimating Genesis, 2.9 hours present speed.
我们能保持这个速度吗? 可以 没问题
Can we hold speed, Scotty? Aye, she's got her second wind now.
扫瞄有无追赶在后的太空舰 扫瞄 没有显示任何太空舰
Scan for vessels in pursuit. Scanning. Indications negative.
我做得对吗?
Did I get it right?
非常好 麦考伊
Great, Bones, just great.
让我们坦白一点
It's time for total truth between us.
这个行星并不如你期望一般 对吧?
This planet is not what you intended or hoped for, is it?
没错
Not exactly.
为什么?
Why?
我在创世星的母岩上用上了原始物质
I used proto-matter in the Genesis matrix.
那种物质非常不稳定 所有科学家都知道...
An unstable substance which every ethical scientist in the galaxy
那是非常危险的材料
has denounced as dangerously unpredictable.
它是唯一能解决问题的方法
It was the only way to solve certain problems.
就像你父亲一样 你擅自违反规定
So, like your father, you changed the rules.
如果不这么做 或许永远都不能实现计划
If I hadn't, it might have been years, or never!
你的性急害苦了多少人?
How many have paid the price for your impatience?
多少人因此而死? 你造成了多少损害?
How many have died? How much damage have you done?
还会发生什么结果?
And what is yet to come?
舰桥 这里什么也没发现
Bridge, nothing happening here.
这个行星正在急速老化 史波克也是
This planet is ageing in surges. And Spock with it.
他们好像结合在一起 没错
It seems they're joined together. They are.
还有多久?
How long?
几天 或许几个小时
Days. Maybe hours.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
史波克会感到很痛苦
It will be hardest on Spock.
很快他就会感觉到 他体内瓦肯血液的燃烧
Soon he will feel the burning of his Vulcan blood.
我不明白 喷发
I don't understand. Pon Farr.
瓦肯男人成年后 他们必须每七年忍受一次
Vulcan males must endure it every seventh year of their adult life.
他们越来越接近了
Whoever they are, they're getting closer.
我去吧 不
I'll go. No.
让我去吧 把武器给我
I'll do it. Give me your phaser.
星际舰队正在通知葛里松号 叫他们提防我们
Sir, Starfleet calling USS Grissom. A warning about us.
他们的回答呢? 跟之前一样 没有回应
Response? Nothing. As before.
葛里松号会怎么做? 支持我们或是攻击我们?
What's the Grissom up to? Will she join us or fire on us?
契可夫 打破沉默 替我向艾斯塔班舰长致意
Chekov, break silence. Send Captain Esteban my compliments.
我们还好吧? 我们还好吧?
How are we doing? How are we doing?
你这种问法真是有趣
Funny you should put it quite that way, Jim.
我们还不错 但是我宁愿让他霸占我的肾脏
We are doing fine. But I'd feel safer
也不喜欢让他占据我的脑袋
giving him one of my kidneys than what's scrambled in my brain.
葛里松号没有任何回应
No response from Grissom on any channel.
每隔一段时间就继续传送
Keep trying. At regular intervals.
终于发生了
So it has come.
这种情形叫喷发
It is called Pon Farr.
喷发
Pon Farr.
你愿意相信我吗?
Will you trust me?
我们安全的以曲速前进 现在正要进入创世星领域
We are secured from Warp Speed. Now entering Genesis Sector.
用推动力前进
Proceed at impulse power.
太空舰进入领域 没错
Vessel entering sector. Yes.
联邦战斗巡航舰 他们有扫瞄到我们吗?
Federation Battle Cruiser. Have they scanned us?
还没有
Not yet.
启动隐形装置
Engage cloaking device.
我发誓那里有些东西
I'd swear there was something there, sir.
你看到了什么?
What did you see?
一刹那间 像一台侦察舰
For an instant, a scout class vessel.
有可能是葛里松号 尝试联络他们
Could be Grissom. Patch in the hailing frequency.
葛里松号 这里是进取号 请回答
Grissom, this is Enterprise calling. Please come in.
葛里松号 这里是进取号 你们有收到吗?
Grissom, this is Enterprise calling. Do you read?
史波克
Spock!
我大老远跑来要寻找创世机
I've come a long way for the power of Genesis.
我找到了什么?
And what do I find?
一个懦弱的人类 一个瓦肯男孩和一个女人
A weakling human, a Vulcan boy and a woman.
我们是考察队的幸存者
My Lord, we are survivors of a doomed expedition.
这个行星很快就会毁灭 创世星实验失败了
This planet will destroy itself soon. The Genesis experiment is a failure.
失败了?
A failure?
这是最强大的毁灭力量
The most powerful destructive force ever created.
你必须告诉我创世机的秘密
You will tell me the secret of the Genesis torpedo.
我完全不知道
I have no knowledge.
那么希望你喜欢享受痛苦
Then I hope pain is something you enjoy.
我下令不准打扰的 但是 司令...
I ordered no interruptions. But, sir...
联邦太空舰正在接近 传我上去
Federation Starship approaching. Bring me up.
葛里松号 这里是进取号 你收到了吗?
Grissom, this is Enterprise calling. Do you read?
葛里松号 这里是进取号 请回答
Grissom, this is Enterprise calling. Please come in.
战争警戒状态
Battle Alert!
葛里松号 这里是进取号
Grissom, this is Enterprise.
寇克将军呼叫艾斯塔班舰长 或是莎维可中尉
Admiral Kirk calling Captain Esteban or Lieutenant Saavik.
报告状态 我们己启动隐形装置
Report status. We are cloaked.
敌方以推动力前进 距离五千太空公里
Enemy closing on impulse power. Range five thousand kellicams.
太好了 这是我期待己久的好机会
Good! This is just the turn of luck I have been waiting for.
我的扫瞄机没有任何发现 短距离扫瞄 契可夫
Nothing on my scanner, sir. Short-range scan, Mr Chekov.
苏鲁 将影像放映出来
Put it on visual, Mr Sulu.
距离三千太空公里
Range three thousand kellicams.
稳定住 继续开启推动力
Steady. Continue on impulse power.
距离两千太空公里
Range two thousand kellicams.
准备开动武器
Stand by to transfer energy to weapons.
听候我的命令
At my command.
那里的星光有些扭曲 看到没?
There! That distortion, see it?
是的 我们越接近 它就越来越大
Yes, sir. It's getting larger as we close in.
己在射程之内
Firing range, sir.
炮手...
Gunner...
只瞄准引擎 明白吗?
Target engine only. Understood?
非常明白 长官
Understood clearly, sir.
你的判断为何? 苏鲁 我猜那是很强的能量
Opinion, Mr Sulu. I think it's an energy surge.
足够隐藏一艘太空舰? 是隐形装置
Enough energy to hide a ship? A cloaking device.
红色警戒 史考特
Red Alert, Mr Scott.
一千太空公里 正在逐渐接近
One thousand kellicams and closing.
所有能量集中到武器系统
All power to the weapons systems.
等等
Wait. Wait.
没有防护罩?
No shields?
如果我猜的没错 他们开火之前得先解除隐形罩
If my guess is right, they'll have to de-cloak before they can fire.
希望你的猜测是正确的
May all your guesses be right.
克林贡的鸟形舰 备有武器 开火 史考特
Klingon Bird of Prey. Arming. Fire, Mr Scott!
射得真准 史考特
Good shooting, Mr Scott.
小心戒备 契可夫 启动防护罩
Precautionary, Mr Chekov, shields up.
开启火箭推进器
Emergency power to the thrusters!
防护罩没有回应 史考特?
Sir, the shield's non-responsive. Scotty?
自动操作系统负荷过多 我并没预期会开战
The automation system's overloaded. I didn't expect combat, you know.
开火
Fire!
紧急电源 准备再次开火
Emergency power. Prepare to return fire.
史考特 可以将电源接到武器系统吗?
Mr Scott, can you transfer power to phaser banks?
恐怕不行 他们击中了自动操作系统
I don't think so. They've knocked out the automation centre.
我已经失去太空舰的控制 苏鲁?
I've got no control over anything. Mr Sulu?
我也没办法 舰长
Nothing, sir.
那么...我们只能坐以待毙
So... we're a sitting duck.
准备发射逃生囊
Ready to fire emergency tube.
为何他们不消灭我们? 他们的火力比我们强大十倍
Why haven't they finished us? They outgun me ten to one!
司令 敌方长官希望议和
My Lord. The enemy commander wishes a truce to confer.
接上他们的影像
Put them on screen.
我是星联进取号的寇克将军
This is Admiral James T. Kirk of the Federation Starship Enterprise.
他是创世计划的指挥官 你们违反了...
The Genesis Commander himself. A violation of treaty...
星联跟克林贡帝国的条约
...between the Federation and the Klingon Empire,
这就等于向我们宣战
...your presence here is an act of war.
你们有两分钟的时间弃舰投降
You have two minutes to surrender your crew and your vessel...
否则我们会击毁你们 他在隐瞒一些东西
...or we will destroy you. He's hiding something.
他们的太空舰有可能已经被严重破坏
We may have dealt him a more serious blow than I thought.
你怎么知道? 我相信我的直觉
How can you tell that? I trust my instincts.
寇克将军 我是敌方的司令
Admiral Kirk, this is your opponent speaking.
别跟我说什么条约了
Don't lecture me about treaty violations!
星联制造那么厉害的武器 就已经是违反条约
In creating an ultimate weapon, the Federation has become criminals!
我不会投降的 你们才应该投降
It is not I who will surrender, it is you!
在那个星球上我们有三个人质
On the planet below, I have three prisoners
他们是制造创世机的成员
from the team who developed your doomsday weapon.
如果你们不投降 我们会处决他们
If you don't surrender, I'll execute them as enemies of galactic peace!
你到底是谁? 竟然够胆俘虏人质
Who is this? How dare you take prisoners?
我是谁并不重要 那些人质才最重要
Who I am is not important. That I have them is.
你可以跟他们通话
You may speak to them.
将军 我是莎维可中尉 莎维可?
Admiral, this is Lieutenant Saavik. Saavik!
大卫跟你在一起吗? 没错 还有另一个人
Is David with you? Yes, and someone else.
一个瓦肯星的科学家 你跟他很熟的
A Vulcan scientist of your acquaintance.
这个瓦肯人...
This... Vulcan...
他还活著吗?
Is he alive?
他不是以前的他了 不过他还活著
He is not himself, but he lives.
他老的非常快 就像这个星球一样
He's subject to rapid ageing, like this unstable planet.
你好 长官 我是大卫
Hello, sir, it's David.
很抱歉我来迟了
I'm sorry I'm late.
我早知道你会来的 没错 这个星球很不稳定
I should've known you'd come. It's true, this planet is unstable.
它在几小时内就会自我毁灭
It's gonna destroy itself within hours.
大卫 创世星有什么问题
David, what went wrong?
那是我的问题 我不明白
I went wrong. I don't understand.
很抱歉 请你千万别投降
I'm sorry, sir. Just don't surrender.
创世计划失败了 我不相信他会杀了我们
Genesis doesn't work. I can't believe they'd kill us for it.
他们都错了 我真的会杀了他们
Admiral, your friend is mistaken, I meant what I said.
为了证明我的决心 我会先杀一个人质
And to show that my intentions are sincere, I shall kill one prisoner.
等一下 让我再说一会...
Wait! Give me a chance to talk...
随便杀一个人质
Kill one of them. I don't care which.
莎维可?
Saavik?
大卫?
David?
将军 大卫已经死了
Admiral... David is dead.
你这个混蛋 你杀了我儿子
You Klingon bastard, you've killed my son.
混蛋 你杀了我儿子
Klingon bastard, you've killed my son!
你这个克林贡混蛋
You Klingon bastard!
还有两个人质 将军
There are two more prisoners, Admiral.
你要他们死吗?
Do you want them killed, too?
弃舰投降吧
Surrender your vessel.
好吧 混蛋
All right. All right, damn you.
好吧
All right.
给我一分钟去告诉我的舰员
Give me a minute to inform my crew.
我给你们两分钟时间
I give two minutes to you and your gallant crew.
集合所有舰员 带备武器 准备登船
Take every last man, form a boarding party, armed heavily!
司令 他们的人数比我们多 我们是克林贡人
They outnumber us, my Lord. We are Klingons!
我们一控制太空舰 就将我们的旗帜搬过去
Once you control the ship we will transfer our flag there
还要拿走他们的创世机程式
and take Genesis from their memory banks.
苏鲁 鸟形舰上有多少人?
Mr Sulu, what is the crew complement of a Bird of Prey?
大约十多个人
About a dozen officers and men.
有一部分已经在创世星上
With some of them on the planet.
我保证我们还未完蛋
I swear to you, we're not finished yet.
麦考伊跟苏鲁到传送室 其他的人跟我来
Bones, you and Sulu to the Transporter Room, the rest with me.
我们要大显身手了
We have a job to do.
克林贡司令 准备上太空舰吧
Commander Klingon vessel. Prepare to board this ship on my next signal.
别使诈 寇克 你还有一分钟
No tricks, Kirk! You have one minute.
我不会使诈 我也很想见你
No tricks. I'm looking forward to meeting you.
到传送室去 祝你们成功
To the Transport Room. Success!
电脑 我是寇克将军 我要求进入系统
Computer, this is Admiral James T. Kirk, requesting security access.
电脑 毁灭程序一号...
Computer, destruct Sequence One, Code: 1...
密码11A
1 A...
电脑 我是总工程师 史考特军官
Computer, Commander Montgomery Scott, Chief Engineering Officer.
毁灭程序二号 密码11A2B
Destruct Sequence Two, Code: 11 A 2B.
电脑 我是临时科学主管 帕维契可夫军官
Computer, this is Commander Pavel Chekov, acting Science Officer.
毁灭程序三号 密码1B2B3
Destruct Sequence Three, Code: 1 B2B3.
毁灭程序己被完成
Destruct Sequence completed and engaged.
等候最后密码 随时开始一分钟倒数
Awaiting final Code for one-minute countdown.
密码000
Code: 000.
毁灭 0
Destruct 0.
毁灭程序己被启动
Destruct Sequence is activated.
寇克 时间到了
Kirk, your time runs out.
切准备妥当? 没错
All set? Aye, sir.
克林贡司令 我们正在开动传送装置
Commander Klingon vessel, we are energising transporter beam, now.
传送装置 准备开动
Transporter, stand by!
司令 他们好像放弃了太空舰
My Lord, the ship appears to be deserted.
怎么可能? 他们只是躲起来
How can that be? They're hiding.
是的 司令 但太空舰好像是被电脑操纵
Yes, sir, but the bridge seems to be run by computer.
它是唯一发出声音的东西 发出声音? 让我听听
It's the only thing speaking. Speaking? Let me hear.
九、八、七、六...
Nine, eight, seven, six...
五 快走...
...five... Get out! Get out of there!
快走...
Get out! ...one...
麦考伊 我做的对吗?
My God, Bones. What have I done?
你别无选择 你一定要那么做
What you had to do. What you always do.
希望死亡能换来生存的机会
Turn death into a fighting chance to live.
行星核心不稳定 正在快速变化
Planet core readings, unstable. Changing rapidly.
行星表面有生命迹象吗?
What about surface life signs?
在那边
There.
别碰他
No! Don't touch him!
麦考伊
Bones.
发生了什么事? 他牺牲自己来救我们
What happened? He gave his life to save us.
他衰老的很快 所有遗传功能都加速了
Rapid ageing. All genetic functions highly accelerated.
他的脑袋呢? 他的脑袋是空的
What about his mind? His mind's a void.
他的灵魂似乎全附在我身上
It seems, Admiral, that I've got all his marbles.
我们能做什么? 只有一件事
Is there anything we can do? Only one thing.
带他离开这里 他的衰老是因为这个行星
Get him off this planet. His ageing is part of what's going on around us.
克林贡司令 我是寇克将军
Klingon Commander, this is Admiral James T. Kirk.
我还活著 正在行星的表面
I'm alive and well on the planet's surface.
你一定会感到很惊奇
I know this will come as a pleasant surprise to you.
太空舰的爆炸只是一个意外
Our ship was a victim of an unfortunate accident.
很抱歉 但生活就是如此
Sorry about your crew, but as we say on Earth, "C'est la vie".
我拥有你想要的东西
I have what you want.
我知道创世机的秘密
I have the secret of Genesis.
你得传送我们到你的太空舰 才能得到它
You're gonna have to bring us up there to get it.
你听到吗?
Do you hear me?
我在等你回答
I'm waiting for you!
你的答案为何?
What is your answer?
放下所有武器
Drop all weapons!
除了寇克之外 全到那边去
Over there, all but Kirk.
犯人已经在传送机的位置
Maltz... Prisoners at beam coordinates.
你该连这个瓦肯星人也送走 不能
You should take the Vulcan too. No!
为什么? 因为这是你的愿望
But why? Because you wish it.
开始传送
Maltz... Activate beam!
我要知道创世机的秘密
Genesis. I want it!
将这个瓦肯星人送走 我们才有得谈
Beam the Vulcan up, and we'll talk.
如果你满足我的要求 我会考虑将他送走
Give me what I want and I'll consider it.
傻瓜 你看看这里 这个行星快要毁灭了
Fool! Look around you! The planet's destroying itself!
没错 这不是很兴奋吗?
Yes, exhilarating, isn't it?
如果我们不互相帮助 我们都会死在这里
If we don't help each other, we'll die here!
太好了 我们就死在这里
Perfect! Then that's the way it shall be.
将创世机给我
Give me Genesis!
把你的手给我 寇克
Give me your hand! Kirk!
我已经...
I... have had...
受够你了
...enough of you!
传送
Maltz!
别动 还有多少人?
Don't! How many more?
只有他而己
Just him, sir.
麦考伊 看看史波克
Bones, help Spock.
我们必须脱离轨道
We've got to break out of orbit.
你不帮我们 我们就杀了你
You, help us or die.
我是该死的
I do not deserve to live.
好 我迟些才杀你 你现在给我滚
Fine, I'll kill you later. Let's get out of here.
哪个是反物质装置? 这个吗?
Where's the anti-matter inducer? This?
不是 是这个
No! This!
看看运气了
That or nothing.
如果我没有看错 我们有最高能量了
If I read this right, sir, we have full power.
那就马上离开 苏鲁
Go, Sulu.
再见了 大卫
Goodbye, David.
我们已经安全 可以自由驾驶
We are clear and free to navigate.
全速飞往瓦肯星 契可夫 把犯人带走
Best speed to Vulcan. Mr Chekov, take the prisoner below.
等等 你刚才说会杀了我 我骗你的
Wait! You said you would kill me. I lied.
史波克...
Spock...
看在老天份上 跟我说说话吧
For God's sake, talk to me!
你把你的灵魂附在我的身上 记得吗?
You stuck this damn thing in my head, remember?
记得吗?
Remember?
告诉我应该怎么做
Now, tell me what to do with it.
帮帮我
Help me.
我有些话必须告诉你...
I'm gonna tell you something that I...
我从未想过我会这么说
...never thought I'd hear myself say.
但是我很想念你
But it seems I've missed you.
我不能忍受再次失去你
I don't know if I could stand to lose you again.
他们正往这里来
Ambassador, they are on approach.
他们要求批准降落
They're requesting permission to land.
批准 告诉他们...
Permission granted. Tell them...
告诉寇克 我们准备好了
Tell Kirk we'll be ready.
苏鲁 你正在手动驾驶
Mr Sulu, you're on manual.
己驾驶一段时间了 就是这里
It's been a while, sir. Here we go.
逆向推进器
Retrothrusters.
沙瑞克己在上头等候
Sarek is waiting above, sir.
沙瑞克...
Sarek...
史贡的孩子 苏卡尔的孩子...
Child of Skon, child of Solkar...
你儿子的躯体仍有气息
The body of your son breathes still.
你的愿望是什么?
What is your wish?
我要求你施展浮图邦法术
I ask for Fal-Tor-Pan. The refusion.
这种法术己很久没有用过
What you seek has not been done since ages past,
而且只有在传说中才存在
and then only in legend.
你的请求太不合理了
Your request is not logical.
诘原谅我 女祭司
Forgive me, T'Lar.
关于我儿子的事 我是不讲逻辑的
My logic is uncertain where my son is concerned.
谁是他灵魂的看守人?
Who is the keeper of the Katra?
是我
I am.
雷纳得麦考伊 大卫的儿子
McCoy, Leonard H., son of David.
麦考伊 大卫的儿子
McCoy, Son of David...
因为你是地球人
Since thou art human, we cannot expect thee
我们不期望你会完全了解沙瑞克的请求
to understand fully what Sarek has requested.
史波克的躯体仍然活著
Spock's body lives.
如果你愿意的话我们将会尽全力...
With your approval, we shall use all our powers
将他的灵魂从你身上归回原处
to return to his body that which you possess.
但是你必须知道
But McCoy, you must now be warned.
你跟他都会有极大的危险
The danger to thyself is as grave as the danger to Spock.
你必须作出选择
You must make the choice.
我选择冒险
I choose the danger.
问得可真好
Hell of a time to ask.
我没事的 寇克
I'm all right, Jim.
史波克怎样了?
What about Spock?
只有时间能证明
Only time will answer.
寇克...我很感谢你你所做的事...
Kirk... I thank you. What you have done is...
我所做的事...
What I have done...
我必须那么做
...I had to do.
但代价是什么呢?
But at what cost?
你的星舰和你的儿子
Your ship. Your son.
如果我不尝试的话...我将会良心不安
If I hadn't tried... the cost would have been my soul.
我父亲说你是我的朋友
My father says that you have been my friend.
你是为了我而来的
You came back for me.
你也会为我这么做的
You would have done the same for me.
为什么你会这么做呢?
Why would you do this?
因为牺牲小我...
Because the needs of the one...
才能成全大我
...outweigh the needs of the many.
我曾经是...
I have been...
也永远是你的朋友
...and ever shall be your friend.
没错
Yes.
没错 史波克
Yes, Spock!
星舰安全脱险吗?
The ship. Out of danger?
你拯救了星舰
You saved the ship.
你拯救了大家 你不记得吗?
You saved us all. Don't you remember?
吉姆
Jim.
你的名字叫吉姆
Your name is Jim.
是的
Yes.